（不動(ふどう) 明(あきら)の笑い声）
MIXED BATHING SPRINGS
CAPYBARAS & HUMANS
（明）わーい
（明の笑い声）
（飛鳥(あすか) 了(りょう)）お前なら
ここへ来てくれると思ったよ
I thought you would come here.
（明）なぜ人間を裏切った？
Why did you betray the humans?
You drove them mad by making them scared.
人間に恐怖を吹き込み
狂わせた！？
Humans are weak.
Their extinction is inevitable.
人間は弱い
滅びるのは必然だ
Don't be ridiculous! You're human, too!
ふざけるな！
お前だって人間だろうが！
それが違うんだ 明
I'm not, Akira.
あ…
（サタン）私はサタンだ
I'm Satan.
かつて氷のごとく冷たき神へ
戦を挑み―
I challenged the icy cold God
some time ago.
天を追われ 暗い宇宙をさまよい
この地にやってきた
I was cast from Heaven,
wandered the dark universe,
and came to Earth.
人間が誕生する はるか以前
この星を支配していたのは―
Long before humans existed,
this world was dominated by...
悪魔だった
demons.
（悪魔）ぐわあああ！
Weakness meant death.
（サタン）弱さは死を意味し
強い者だけが生き残る
Only the strong survived.
It is the history of power.
力の歴史だ
悪魔は この戦いの世界で
生き残るために―
In order to survive this world of battle,
demons gained a special ability.
特殊な能力を身につけた
They gained the characteristics of
other organisms by merging with them.
他の生物と合体して
その体質を手に入れていったのだ
人間が武器を進化させたように―
Just as humans developed weapons,
悪魔は合体によって 自らの体を
強力な武器に変えていった
demons changed their own bodies
into powerful weapons by this merging.
私は悪魔たちの
単純明快な心が気に入り―
I liked the demons' simple
and straightforward hearts,
ここに身を落ち着けたが
無慈悲な神は―
and settled down here.
But unmerciful God
この辺境の地までも 我々が
存在することを許しはしなかった
did not allow us to exist,
even on this outpost of a planet.
しかし 我々は死んではいなかった
But we were not dead.
意思としてとどまり やがて
地上へ人間が現れ始めると―
We remained as pure will.
Eventually, when humans appeared on Earth,
we substantialized ourselves
by merging with humans,
再び人類の身と合体することで
実体化し―
存在を取り戻していった
and began to regain existence.
The legends of werewolves,
vampires, and ogres
狼男や吸血鬼 鬼の伝説も―
悪魔が人間と合体した姿だろう
are all forms of demons
merged with humans.
もっと古代 不思議な痕跡から―
Further back in antiquity
were people who learned of us
我々の存在をつかんだ者もいた
from our many strange remains.
I came back into existence,
（サタン）私も蘇ったが―
サタンである記憶の扉は
固く閉ざされていた
but the memory of being Satan
was locked away in my mind.
However...
しかし…
I instinctively eliminated those
who tried to kill me.
命を狙う者たちを本能で退けた
（明）大丈夫？
Are you okay?
（明）大丈夫 怖くないよ
It's okay.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Don't be afraid.
怖くない 怖くない
（サタン）ジェニーに
連れられたあとも―
Even after Jenny took me away,
サタンである記憶は
戻らなかったが―
I didn't recover any memory of
being Satan, but subconsciously,
無意識のうちに
悪魔復活の作戦を実行していたのだ
I was putting a plan
to revive demons into action.
しかし よくよく神は無慈悲で―
But God was very unmerciful.
私のことが嫌いらしい
I guess God hates me.
悪魔が復活しているのを知り
再び攻撃を開始した
God found out that the demons were revived
and he began to attack again.
人間には手を下さず
我々だけを狙って
He didn't kill humans,
but aimed to destroy only us.
Akira, humans will perish.
明… 人間は滅びる
お前は我々と生きるしかない
You must live with us.
（明）悪魔につけというのか！
You want me to be a demon?
お前は悪魔だ　人間ではない
You are a demon, not a human.
俺は人間だ！
I'm a human!
お前が悪魔の体にしたんだ
You made my body into a demon.
（サタン）最強の器だぞ
It is the strongest vessel.
家族も 友も 愛する人も
全て失った…
My family, my friends,
and the person that I loved.
I lost everyone.
悪魔のせいで
All because of demons.
Akira.
Let's live in the new world together.
明 新しい世界を共に生きよう
そのために お前を
英雄アモンと合体させたのだ
I made you merge with the champion,
Amon, for that reason.
ううっ
さあ 明！
Come, Akira!
ふざけるな～！
You're full of shit!
（デビルマン）
お前は俺の一番大事なものを奪った
You robbed me of my most important thing.
お前のために泣いてやりてえが―
I would like to cry for you...
もう涙も枯れ果てた
but my tears have all dried up.
お前と戦うつもりはない
I do not intend to fight you.
俺はお前を
ぶちのめしたくてたまんねえぜ
I'm dying to beat the hell out of you.
お前らなんかに人間は負けねえ
Humans won't lose to demons like you.
必ず俺が
てめえらを滅ぼしてやる！
I swear I'm going to destroy you all.
If you make me your enemy,
私を敵に回すと… 死ぬぞ
you'll die.
ヘッ そうだとしても―
Even if that's the case,
必ずお前も一緒に
地獄へ引きずり込んでやるぜ！
I will definitely drag you down
to hell with me.
（サタン）後悔するぞ
You will regret this.
今度会った時 必ずお前を殺す
The next time I see you,
I'm going to kill you..
（サイコジェニー）
よろしいのですか？
Is all well?
構わん
It is.
Who was it that destroyed my apartment?
私のマンションを破壊した連中は？
It was Xenon's men.
（サイコジェニー）
ゼノンの部下たちでした
すでに粛正完了しております
They have already been annihilated.
My apologies for not
detecting their frustrations.
不満を察知しきれず
申し訳ありません…
（サタン）よい　原因は私だ
No.
The fault is mine.
CRYBABY
（ワム）ヒーローのお守りだ
This will protect you.
Will it work?
（牧村(まきむら)美樹(みき)）効くかな？
（ワム）無敵さ
Of course it will.
（ターコ）明さん 揃いました
Akira, everyone is here.
They're all Devilmen
who gathered because of Miki's appeal.
皆 美樹さんの呼びかけに答えた
デビルマンです
（明）俺は 人間が
悪魔に滅ぼされるのを―
I don't intend to quietly watch humans
being destroyed by demons.
黙って見ているつもりはない
この手で悪魔どもを
ぶっつぶしてやる
I'll destroy the demons
with my own hands.
（デビルマンたちの歓声）
We will fight, too.
（修行僧デビルマン）
私たちも戦います！
世界中のデビルマンが
この戦いに参加するでしょう
All Devilmen around the world
will join this battle.
（陸上部監督）悪魔どもめ～！
Foolish demons!
The Devilmen won't let you have your way.
デビルマンが
お前らの好きにはさせんぞ！
（デビルマンたちの歓声）
（英語：戦車長）我が国の首都を
占拠しているのは人間ではない！
これは反乱行為にあらず！
（英語：軍人１）首都をおびやかす
悪魔を壊滅せよ！
（英語：軍人２）
悪魔による反乱を壊滅せよ！
（銃撃の音）
（サイコジェニー）始まりました
It has begun.
愚かで弱い人間たちは
自分たちで数を減らしていきます
The foolish and weak humans
are annihilating themselves.
Just as I had expected.
思った通りだ
Satan, you have lived with humans,
（サイコジェニー）
サタン様は人間と暮らし―
弱点を熟知されておいででした
and are familiar
with their weaknesses.
お見事です
Bravo.
私は先の戦いで傷つかれ―
Since you were wounded in battle,
もう戻られないのではと
危惧しておりました
I feared you would not return.
（サタン）私はあきらめていない
I have not given up.
人間を滅ぼしたあと―
After we destroy the humans,
再び我らは
存在をかけて神と戦う
we will battle God again
for our existence.
急がなくては
We must hurry.
Eat all the humans before God gets here.
（デーモン１）神が来る前に
人間どもを食らいつくせ！
う ああ…
Knock it down.
（デーモン２）たたき落とせ！
うう… ぬぅっ…
A nuclear bomb.
核爆弾！？
（悪魔１）ヒドラだ！
It's Hydra.
あの方が来た！
（悪魔２）お目覚めになったぞ！
He's here.
He's awakened.
（悪魔３）我々の勝利だ！
It's our victory!
Satan is an angel
who challenged God to fight in the past.
（ターコ）サタンはかつて１人で
神に戦いを挑んだ天使です
It is said he came to Earth
because he lost.
敗れて地球へやってきたと
いわれていますが―
He is noble, beautiful, and benign,
and said to have 12 feathers.
気高く美しく 両性を持ち―
12の羽を持つといわれています
（パイロット）何だ あれは
What is that?
（乗務員）これも悪魔か？
Another demon?
（サイコジェニー）
はびこる人間どもめ
Rampant humans...
We should be the only ones
who exist on this Earth.
この地球に存在するのは
我々だけでよい
（乗務員たちのうめき声）
I found you. The last human beings.
（サイコジェニー）
見つけたぞ 最後の人間ども
You still resist?
まだあがくか
Devilman.
デビルマン！
了～！
Ryo!
You fool!
（幸田(こうだ)マン）バカめ！
The weak die
and the strong survive.
強いヤツが生き
弱いヤツが死ぬのが―
That's the way of the world.
この世のルールだ！
ならば こちらへ
つくべきだったな！
Then you're on the wrong side!
（幸田マン）うああああ！
（デビルマン）うわあああ！
（サイコジェニー）
サタン様 ここは私が
Satan, leave this to me.
君は本戦へ加われ
You should join the main war.
（サイコジェニー）
不動 明は無視するのがよいかと
It would be better
if you ignore Akira Fudo.
Go.
行け
（サイコジェニー）はっ
Yes, sir.
Akira. Are you sure you want to fight me?
明 本当に私と戦う気か？
Ryo!
（デビルマン）了～！
（サタン）チッ
（デビルマン）ああっ
（デーモンたちの声）
（女）ひいいっ
ううっ
（学者たち）うわあっ
（デーモン）仲間か！？
Is it their gang?
I'm...
私は… デビルマンだ！
Devilman!
（乗務員たちの苦しむ声）
Forgive me!
（乗務員１）苦しい
Help me!
（乗務員２）助けてくれ！
（銃声）
I won't let you.
（男）なまりは通さねえ
おええ…
（ギドラとヒドラのうめき声）
（デビルマン）おおっ
Please, use me.
（蛇デビルマン）
私をお使いください
うわああ！
うおっ
おおっ！
Use us.
（足のデビルマン）我らを！
（デビルマン）おおっ おりゃ！
うわあっ
（無音の会話）
うああ…
（デビルマン）ぬうああああ！
ふん！
（デビルマン）うああああ！
You can see the stars clearly.
星がよく見える…
人間が滅びてしまったせいだな
It's because all the humans are gone.
あれではウサギは死んでしまったな
The rabbit is probably dead.
Look, Ryo.
了ちゃん ほら ウサギさん
A rabbit.
There's no rabbit.
（了）そんなものはない
（明）え？
（了）あれは月表面の高低差が
陰影になってるだけだ
Those are shadows on the moon's surface,
due to elevation.
そもそも月には空気がない
The moon has no atmosphere.
Then we've got to save them.
じゃあ助けてあげなくちゃ
Akira.
明 あの空には
ウサギなんていない
There's no rabbit in that sky.
俺はこの目で見てきたんだ
I saw it with my own eyes.
（女の子の泣き声）
（明）よしよし
It's okay.
（明の泣き声）
（明）どうして丸いの？
Why does it form circles?
It's the pinhole theory.
（了）ピンホールの要領だ
（明）ようりょう…
Theory?
葉っぱの隙間が
針のように小さいから―
Since the spaces are small like pinholes,
そこを点対称として
太陽の形が逆さまに映ってるんだ
they act like points of symmetry,
and reflect the sun upside-down
on the ground.
てんたい…
Point of...
（了）もうダメだ 死ぬ
It's over. It's going to die.
（明）いや ダメ
-No! Stop!
-It's going to die soon. Give it to me.
もう死ぬんだ 寄こせ
（明）ダメ！
No!
（了）殺してやる
I'll kill it.
（明）ダメ ダメ！
No! Stop!
クソッ 何でだ！
Damn it. Why?
（明）ええ… えーん えーん
AKIRA
ああ… あっく… えーん
（了）どうして泣く？
死ぬのは分かってた
Why are you crying?
You knew it was gonna die.
You're wrong.
（明）違う
（了）弱い者は死ぬ
The weak ones die.
（明）違う 違う 違う！
了ちゃんも泣いてる
No! No! No!
Ryo, you're crying, too.
何で？ 俺は悲しくない
当然のことだ
Why? I'm not sad. It's obvious.
（明）了ちゃんも泣いてる
Ryo, you're crying, too.
（サタン）あの時 俺は―
Back then,
お前が何を言ってるのか
分からなかったよ
I didn't know what you meant.
Love doesn't exist.
There's no such thing as love.
愛はない
愛などない
故に悲しみもない
Therefore, there's no sorrow.
そう思っていた
That's what I thought.
明 俺ばっかりにしゃべらせるな
Akira.
Why am I the only one talking?
Akira?
明？
明…
Akira.
俺は今―
Right now...
何かを感じているよ…
I'm feeling something.
これは何だ？
What is this?
教えろ　何だ 明？
Tell me. What is this, Akira?
今の俺の気持ちを感じてくれ
Feel what I'm feeling right now.
話を聞いてくれ 明
Listen to me.
Akira.
俺を見ろ
Look at me.
何か答えろ
Respond to me.
今まで俺と一緒にいたことを
忘れるな
Don't forget that
you've been with me till now.
何か言え
Say something.
イヤだよ！ 明
No, Akira.
Don't leave me alone.
俺を独りぼっちにするな
置いていくな！
Don't leave me.
どこかにいてくれ！
Please, be somewhere.
何か言ってくれ！
Say something!
明～！ うっ うっ…
Akira!
&lrm;
&lrm;日本語字幕　後藤 太郎
THE END
Subtitle translation by
SDI